Guide to the Meriden Gravure Company Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Estimates, circa 1930-1977; Series V; 39.51; (43 boxes)
  Series V. Estimates is comprised of worksheets, correspondence and index cards pertaining to the estimation of print job costs from circa 1930 to 1977. Though dates are not present on all estimate worksheets, bundles of sheets were dated on the outer packaging. In the Estimators' Worksheets: Chronological subseries, gaps exist between 1933 and 1936 and also between 1940 and 1954.
  - Estimators' Worksheets: Alphabetical, 1930-1967
    - American Hardware Corporation - Bittner, 1931-1954 (Box 199)
    - British - Carnegie, 1930-1954 (Box 200)
    - Case - Columbia, 1931-1954 (Box 201)
    - Columbia - Derrydale, 1931-1954 (Box 202)
    - Derrydale - George, 1931-1949 (Box 203)
    - General Electric, 1949-1954 (Box 204)
    - General Electric - International Silver Company, 1931-1955 (Box 205)
    - Merrymount Press - University of Pennsylvania Museum, 1931-1954 (Box 206)
    - Perleberg - S.N.E. Telephone, 1933-1967 (Box 207)
    - Southwest - Vincent Curtis, 1933-1954 (Box 208)
    - Vincent Curtis - Yale, 1933-1954 (Box 209)
  - Estimators' Worksheets: Chronological, 1930-1955
    Estimators' Worksheets: Chronological are arranged also by order number.
    - 1930 100-133, 1931 A134-A300, 1930-1931 (Box 210)
    - A301-A500, 1931 (Box 211)
    - A501-A599, A801-A838, 1931 (Box 212)
    - A839-A998, 1931 (Box 213)
    - B102-B235, 1932 (Box 214)
    - B236-B389, 1932 (Box 215)
    - B390-B499, 1932 (Box 216)
    - B500-B599, 1932 (Box 217)
    - C1-C152, 1933 (Box 218)
    - C155-C299, 1933 (Box 219)
    - C300-C399, 1933 (Box 220)
    - C401-C499, 1933 (Box 221)
    - F2-F475, 1936 (Box 222)
    - G1-G360, 1937 (Box 223)
    - 1937 G361-G488, 1938 H1-H82, 1937-1938 (Box 224)
    - H83-H469, 1938 (Box 225)
    - I2-I389, 1939 (Box 226)
    - J2-J314, 1940 (Box 227)
    - 1954 K3-K520, 1955 L4-L532, 1954-1955 (Box 228)
  - Other Estimates, 1933-1977
    - Estimate Books, General, 1933-1935 (Box 229)
    - Estimate Books, General, 1937-1939 (Box 230)
    - Estimate Books, General, 1940-1946 (Box 231)
    - Estimate Books, General, 1946-1950 (Box 232)
    - Estimate Books, General, Commercial and Scientific, 1951-1955 (Box 233)
    - Estimate Books, Commercial and Scientific, 1956-1959 (Box 234)
    - Estimate Books, Commercial and Scientific, 1960-1969 (Box 235)
    - Estimate Books, Commercial and Scientific, 1970-1976 (Box 236)
    - Estimate Books, Commercial and Scientific, General Electric, New Britain Machine Company, Pratt and Whitney, and Princeton University, 1949-1963, 1977 (Box 237)
    - Estimate Books, State and U. S. Government and Transfers, 1949-1953 (Box 238)
    - Estimate Cards, 1930-1939 (Box 239)
    - Estimate Cards, circa 1940-1955 (Box 240)
    - Estimate Correspondence, circa 1950-1975 (Box 241)
- Recapitulation Forms, 1937-1957, undated; Series VI; 42.18; (46 boxes)
  Series VI. is arranged chronologically and by order number. Typically each year has a corresponding letter beginning the order numbers. Some order numbers seem to be out of sequence, and were arranged according to the date on the outer packaging. In cases where bundles were not dated, sheets are arranged by order number.
  Series VI. Recapitulation Forms contains cost recapitulation forms spanning 1937 to 1957. Though dates are not present on all forms, bundles of sheets were dated on the outer packaging. There is a significant gap in the records between 1951 and 1957.
  - "R"-"S", 1937-1939 (Box 242)
  - "S"-"T", 1939 (Box 243)
  - "T", 1939 (Box 244)
  - "T", 1939 (Box 245)
  - "B", "U", 1940 (Box 246)
  - "U", 1940 (Box 247)
  - "U", "A", 1940-1941 (Box 248)
  - "A", 1941 (Box 249)
  - "H", 1941 (Box 250)
  - "B"-"C", 1942-1943 (Box 251)
  - "C", 1943 (Box 252)
  - "C"-"D", 1943-1944 (Box 253)
  - "D", 1943-1944 (Box 254)
  - "D", 1944 (Box 255)
  - "D", 1944 (Box 256)
  - "E", 1945 (Box 257)
  - "E"-"F", 1946 (Box 258)
  - "F"-"G", 1946-1947 (Box 259)
  - "G", 1947 (Box 260)
  - "G"-"H", 1947-1949 (Box 261)
  - "H", 1949 (Box 262)
  - "H", 1949 (Box 263)
  - "J", 1949 (Box 264)
  - "J", 1949 (Box 265)
  - "J", 1949 (Box 266)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 267)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 268)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 269)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 270)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 271)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 272)
  - "L", 1951 (Box 273)
  - "T", 1957 (Box 274)
  - "T", 1957 (Box 275)
  - "T", 1957 (Box 276)
  - "A"-"C", "E", undated (Box 277)
  - "E", undated (Box 278)
  - "K", undated (Box 279)
  - "K", undated (Box 280)
  - "K", undated (Box 281)
  - "K", undated (Box 282)
  - "K", undated (Box 283)
  - "K", undated (Box 284)
  - "K", undated (Box 285)
  - "K", undated (Box 286)
  - "S"-"U", "T", undated (Box 287)
- Financial and Business Records, 1895-1977; Series VII; 18.44; (17 boxes)
  Series VII. is arranged roughly by format.
  Series VII. Financial and Business Records contains general records, office records (concerning operation of the printing presses), scientific customer information forms, ledger sheets and balance books, and transfer and shipment reports. Highlights include a map of the Meriden Gravure Company building from 1908 and log books documenting the earliest Meriden Gravure print jobs, from 1897 to 1919.
  - Layout of Building, "Collotype Printing" by Arthur Sias, 1908, undated (Box 288)
  - General Records, 1952-1957 (Box 289)
  - General Records, 1958-1962 (Box 290)
  - General Records, 1963-1967 (Box 291)
  - Monthly Reports of Shipments, 1961-1974 (Box 292)
  - Office Records, 1895-1900 (Box 293)
  - Office Records, 1901-1905 (Box 294)
  - Office Records, 1906-1910 (Box 295)
  - Office Records, 1911-1915 (Box 296)
  - Office Records, 1916-1922 (Box 297)
  - Scientific Customer Information, 1933-1942 (Box 298)
  - Scientific Customer Information, Insurance Reports, 1933-1942, 1969-1974 (Box 299)
  - Transfers 1931-1957, General Ledger Sheets 1945-1965, 1931-1965 (Box 300)
  - General Ledger Sheets 1967-1969, Print Jobs 1897-1919, 1897-1969 (Box 301)
  - Sales Book, 1951-1952 (Box 302)
  - Sales Book, 1953-1954 (Box 303)
  - Trial Balance Book, 1954-1977 (Box 304)
- Printed Material, 1907-1974; Series VIII; 57.4; (55 boxes)
  Series VIII. is organized into four subseries: Proofs, Silver Catalogs, Post Cards, and Miscellaneous Printed Material.
  Series VIII. Printed Material contains proofs, file copies, and final copies of material printed by Meriden Gravure Company, spanning 1907 to 1974. It includes proofs of Leonard Baskin's illustrations for Dante's Divine Comedy, proofs of dog sketches by Marguerite Kirmse, and proofs of silver catalogs from 1907 to 1941.
  - Proofs, 1967-1974, undated
    - Proofs, 1967-1974 (Box 305)
    - Proofs, 1967-1974 (Box 306)
    - Proofs, 1971 February - July (Box 307)
    - Proofs, 1971 August - 1972 April (Box 308)
    - Proofs, 1972 May - December (Box 309)
    - Proofs, 1973 January - June (Box 310)
    - Proofs, 1973 July - December (Box 311)
    - Proofs, 1974 (Box 312)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 312a (Broadside))
    - Proofs "J415," Georgia Museum of Art, undated (Box 313)
    - National Portrait Gallery Proofs, undated (Box 314)
    - Kirmse, Marguerite, b. 1885. Proofs of sketches., undated (Box 315)
    - Baskin, Leonard. Proofs, undated
      - The Divine Comedy - Inferno, undated (Box 316)
      - The Divine Comedy - Purgatorio, undated (Box 317)
      - The Divine Comedy - Paradiso, undated (Box 318)
      - The Divine Comedy miscellaneous, undated (Box 319)
      - The Divine Comedy miscellaneous, undated (Box 320)
      - Miscellaneous Baskin Proofs, undated (Box 321)
    - Final collotype printed by the Meriden Gravure Company, 1967 (Box 321a (Broadside))
      Proof sheet featuring various Bernard Picture Company images. Signed by five Meriden Gravure employees.
  - Silver Catalogs, 1907-1941
    - Barbour Sterling Factory Books, 1920-1927 (Box 322)
    - Barbour Sterling Factory Photographs, 1930-1931 (Box 323)
    - Derby Silver Co. Factory "B", Holmes & Edwards Book, 1924-1932 (Box 324)
    - Holmes & Edwards Book, 1907-1930 (Box 325)
    - International Factory "W", 1921-1928 (Box 326)
    - Meriden Brittania "Church Goods" book, Meriden Brittania "Regular" book, R. Wallace & Sons' Sterling, 1923-1941 (Box 327)
    - R. Wallace & Sons' Sterling, 1928-1940 (Box 328)
    - Simpson Factory "L", 1920-1930 (Box 329)
    - Simpson Factory "L", 1922-1932 (Box 330)
    - Watrous International Factory "P", 1921-1930 (Box 331)
    - Unbound Silver Catalog Pages, 1926-1936 (Box 332)
    - Unbound Silver Catalog Pages, 1922-1940 (Box 333)
  - Post Cards, undated
    Post Cards are arranged alphabetically by client name.
    - A - Brookgreen, undated (Box 334)
    - Brooklyn - Collinsville, undated (Box 335)
    - Collinsville - Florida, undated (Box 336)
    - Florida - Frick, undated (Box 337)
    - Frick - Holy, undated (Box 338)
    - Holy - Murphy, undated (Box 339)
    - Murphy - Pope, undated (Box 340)
    - Poplars - University, undated (Box 341)
    - Van Dyk - Whitman, undated (Box 342)
    - Whitman, undated (Box 343)
    - Miscellaneous Postcards and Postcard Portfolio, 1937, 1958 (Box 344)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1947-1948, undated
    - Partially Identified Printed Material, undated (Box 345)
    - Partially Identified Printed Material, undated (Box 346)
    - Dated Greek Manuscripts, Volumes I - IV, undated (Box 347)
    - Dated Greek Manuscripts, Volumes V - VII, undated (Box 348)
    - Dated Greek Manuscripts, Volumes VIII - IX, undated (Box 349)
    - Lithograph prints by H. Fletcher. Framed., undated (Box Art)
    - "Melville on Piranesi", undated (Box 350)
    - Modern Industry magazine, 1947-1948 (Box 351)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 352)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 353)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 354)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 355)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 356)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 357)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 358)
    - Unidentified Printed Material, undated (Box 359)
- Meriden-Stinehour, Inc. Records, 1974-1990, undated; Series IX; 1; (1 box)
  Series IX. Meriden-Stinehour, Inc. Records consists of one box of materials documenting the operations of Meriden-Stinehour, Inc. Included are financial statements and miscellaneous printed materials.
  - Meriden-Stinehour, Inc. records and printed material, 1974-1990, undated (Box 360)